Can you believe that?
No way!
Morning!
Lovely day, huh?
Good morning.
And yes, it is.
Hmm...
Why do you sound so distant, Maki-kun?
I, uh... dunno.
S-Say, Yuu-chin...
I feel like I should ask.
By "Maki-kun," you don't mean...
Huh? Come on, Ninacchi.
I mean Maehara-kun, obviously.
Maehara Maki-kun.
You still haven't memorized his name?
O-Of course I have.
We hashed it out
and became friends, right?
Right.
You can't be serious.
He and Amami-san are friends?
What if he's blackmailing her?
With what dirt?
Don't ask me. I can't think of anything.
Welp, this is all weird now.
Wait...
What happened after you got away
from me yesterday?
Well...
That's a secret!
That just makes me wanna know even more!
SEE YOU ON FRIDAY
YEAH, THANKS
(TODAY)
SORRY ABOUT YUU
Sorry about Yuu.
Come on, tell me.
Even if I did, you'd just forget.
I would not!
Wow, it's true!
I can't believe nobody's here!
Good sunlight, and there's even seating.
This is a sweet little spot.
I'm glad you like it.
I never expected to be eating lunch
with these two.
Maki-kun, wanna eat lunch with me today?
What?
Wait, Yuu!
That sounds like a bad idea.
Is it?
Maki-kun said he didn't like big groups,
The hell?
Talk about beauty and the beast.
so I figured he'd rather
it was just the two of us.
He must've pulled something underhanded.
Is that so bad?
I mean, it's not bad per se...
But you see the problem,
right, Maehara-kun?
Y-Yeah...
And I think I'd be too nervous, too.
You heard the guy.
Hm...
Oh, I know! Why don't you join us, Umi?
What?
You were there with us yesterday.
Is that okay, Maki-kun?
Huh? Uh...
Sure. The three of us can
eat together today.
Really?
Hooray!
It'll attract unwanted attention if I'm
seen with Asanagi-san and Amami-san,
so I invited them to my
favorite loner meal spot.
Hey!
Your rolled omelets look yummy, Maki-kun!
Wanna trade for one of my wieners?
Huh? I mean, sure.
But I don't know if you'll like it.
Wait, did you make that lunch yourself?
I do sometimes.
My mom's work keeps her busy.
Oh, no, Yuu! Maki-kun's
beating us on homemaker skills!
Can you not lump me in with you?
Whoa!
This omelet's delicious!
It's just the right balance of sweet
and salty to go with white rice.
What?
Can I have one too, Maehara-kun?
Go ahead.
Well?
It's unfairly good.
Wow, you make sweets too, Maki-kun?
What's something you made recently
that you thought came out well?
Well...
The souffle pancakes I made
using just bananas and eggs, maybe?
YUU
I dabble in making sweets,
and I'm pretty decent,
so I thought I could compete...
But nope. I didn't stand a chance.
Don't give up! It's just a flesh wound!
It's not that complicated.
I just watch online tutorials and
follow a few simple steps.
Boo, Maki-kun. You make it sound so easy.
Must be nice! Hearing about it
just makes me wanna try some!
Oh, pancakes...
If you want to try them so badly,
I can make some for you.
What? Really?!
Hooray!
Pan-pa-pa-pan-pa-pa!
Oh, can I come over today, then?
Uh...
Sure.
Thanks! I'm so excited!
Oh, Umi can come too, right?
Yeah.
Let me go buy some tea!
She's a good girl, isn't she?
Yeah. I knew she was the cheery sort,
but now I'm starting to see she's...
Like a big dog?
Maehara, you're not taking
any heat because of her, right?
Like, Yuu's not the type to have
any regard for what people think.
Eh, I was an outcast to begin with.
And it's not like I've been
harassed or anything.
Let me know if anything like that happens.
I think it'll be fine.
You never know.
After all, we're talking about Amami-san.
The number-one prettiest in the class.
Hm?
Come on, everyone's saying it, right?
It'd be weirder if I hadn't heard.
Yeah. Nobody knows who first
started saying it, but it caught on.
The prettiest girl in class, Amami-san,
and the second prettiest...
It's just people talking crap in class.
It's not worth taking to heart.
I dunno. It feels pretty accurate to me.
Even from a girl's perspective, Yuu's
always been the prettiest little thing.
She's got the cutest personality, too.
But I think—
So I'm sure...
You'll come to love her in no time, too.
You mean...
I'm back!
...as a friend, right?
The vending machine had a bunch of teas,
so I bought the most fun-looking one.
Why'd you suddenly take
an interest in Maehara-kun, anyway?
Because he's nice!
He thinks for himself, and he looks
you in the eye when speaking.
He's kind of like Umi.
You think?
Here you go.
Wow!
Thanks, Maki-kun!
Okay.
Let's eat!
Whoa, these are so fluffy!
Umi, this is scary good!
Yep, delicious!
You're amazing, Maki-kun.
I could look at a recipe
all day long and still mess it up.
Because you skip over the details.
Grr.
Like you didn't make a bunch
of charcoal last Valentine's Day.
Don't call my cookies charcoal!
Valentine's Day?
Oh, it was just a bunch of us girls
giving each other friendship chocolate.
That was fun, huh?
Oh, right.
They went to an all-girls school
until the end of middle school.
Tachibana Girls' is considered
the poshest school around here,
and I believe it's a unified elementary,
middle, and high school.
So why did they both apply
to another high school?
Whoa.
Amami-san, is it really
your first time playing this game?
Sure is.
I kinda figured out how it works.
Over here, Umi-chan.
Catch me if you can!
This girl, I swear!
Um... So I do this and this, and...
Go get her!
What was that attack?!
I found it just now.
I press this and this... and bam!
You got me.
Amami-san, can you
show me that one more time?
It's like...
You press this and hold this,
and then take aim...
Right.
Thanks for having us!
Oh, crud!
What?
I forgot to ask.
You see, I wanna treat
Maki-kun to something, too.
Even if I can't make it myself,
I can take him someplace nice.
Just so you know,
I'm not tagging along anymore.
What?!
You two will be just fine without me.
Yuu, you want to get closer
to Maehara-kun, don't you?
Yeah...
Hello?
Sorry about this.
Are you free this Friday?
Okay, got it. Thanks.
Bye-bye.
He was free?
Nah. He said he had plans
with someone already.
Shoot! I forgot my phone!
At Maki-kun's place?
Probably, yeah!
Did you forget something?
See you tomorrow!
Uh... okay?
Oh, remember that manga
you lent me the other day?
It was pretty good.
Right?
I found the final volume being sold before
street date on the way home. Wanna read?
For real?
You should've said that sooner!
Where is it? In your room?
Gimme!
Okay, but I haven't read it yet.
We can read it together, then.
Let's go to your room.
Hurry up. Hurry up!
LOVING TAKAMINE-KUN
Maehara, you can flip the page.
Okay.
I was worried for a moment there,
but I'm glad we got a happy ending.
Yep. Nothing beats the classic approach.
I'm gonna re-read it from the beginning.
Where's volume 1?
Phew. It's been a while since
I binged something like that.
Asanagi, I'm going to make some coffee.
She's asleep.
You're making yourself
way too comfortable.
Wake up, Maki.
Wake up now.
Sorry, Asanagi. I dozed off, too.
Huh. So this girl's Asanagi-san, is she?
I get off work early for the first time
in ages, and what do I find?
You'd better have a good
explanation for this.
Yes, that's right.
They were reading manga
together and dozed off.
Right. I'm so sorry about my son.
Damn, we really conked out, huh?
Sorry. I was meaning to wake you up
when it was time to go.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Umi-chan.
It's really late, so your mother has
agreed to let you stay the night.
What? But...
Go ahead and take a bath first.
I'll leave a pair of my
pajamas outside the door.
Um...
Er...
Don't be shy, now.
Thank you very much.
Maki.
No wonder I kept coming home
on Saturday after an all-nighter
to find this place
smelling of air freshener.
How long have you been
bringing Umi-chan home?
Phrasing.
We started hanging out here
two months ago.
But believe me, we're just friends.
We haven't done anything
you need to worry about.
Listen.
I trust you,
but Umi-chan's a teenage girl.
You need to be more mindful.
Right. I'm sorry.
I'll go apologize to her family tomorrow.
Hey, uh...
Your mother's pajamas didn't fit me,
so I put on some of your sweats instead.
I don't really mind.
I-I'll sleep in the living room.
Feel free to use the bed.
Hold up.
I just woke up and even took a bath,
so I'm fully awake now.
Let's chat a little.
You're such a bad boy, making a girl
as pretty as me spend the night.
It's your fault for sleeping
like a log to begin with.
Though I'm not blameless, either.
Good point.
For a girl, I left myself too defenseless.
Lesson learned.
We're bad kids, huh?
Yeah.
Hey, I've been wondering for a while...
About telling Yuu about our friendship?
Yeah. Were you considering it, too?
It's gonna be hard
to keep it from her much longer.
I'll wait for the right time and tell her.
You just act like usual.
Got it. I'll let you handle it.
Okay, I'm going to bed.
One last thing.
What is it?
Good night, Maehara.
It feels strange actually
saying it out loud.
G-Good night.
Want to sleep in my room?
Huh?!
So, here we are at my place.
I... I'm back home.
Welcome back, Umi.
And good to see you, Maehara-kun.
N-Nice to meet you. I'm Maehara Maki.
What a polite young boy.
I'm Asanagi Sora,
and unfortunately, I'm the mother
of that bad girl next to you.
Listen, Umi. I'm not saying you're
not allowed to have fun.
But you need to keep us up to speed
and not cause us any concern.
Got that?
Yes. I'm really sorry.
I'll be more careful in the future.
As will I.
Good.
Now, Maehara-kun...
How did you and Umi get so close?
Hey!
I've asked Umi, but she just shuts me out,
saying it's none of my business.
Erm...
Maehara! You don't have
to tell her anything!
See? Just like that.
And all I want to know is how my daughter
and her first boyfriend got together.
Th-That wouldn't be any
of your business either!
And you, Maehara. Don't give
this old bag the time of day.
Forget her and have some peaches!
They're nice and sweet!
O-Okay.
It's kind of you to peel them for him
with those clumsy fingers of yours.
No...
Maehara-kun.
Please continue to be friends with Umi.
You know what she's like,
but she's a good kid deep down.
Of course.
Oh, if you don't mind,
why don't you have sleepovers here?
That way, I can watch over you.
It'd help me relax.
A genius idea, if I do say so myself!
Maehara, sew my mom's mouth shut!
I give you permission!
Eek! Help me, Maehara-kun!
Umi's so scawwy!
Argh!
Shut up already!
Now, as you all know,
our school festival's
coming up next month.
SCHOOL FESTIVAL REPS
BOYS:
GIRLS:
Let's go ahead and choose our
class's reps for the event today.
Any volunteers?
I figured not.
So I went ahead and set up a lottery!
WINNER
Sensei, I won.
Oh, okay.
So our boys' rep for the festival
will be Maehara-kun.
SCHOOL FESTIVAL REPS
BOYS:
GIRLS:
I feel so bad for the girls!
Talk about rotten luck.
SCHOOL FESTIVAL REPS
BOYS: MAEHARA MAKI
GIRLS:
Whoever wins has to babysit Maehara.
Is he even gonna be able
to speak up during the meetings?
What a jerk, running his mouth
'cause he has a thing for Yuu-chin.
Please... Please no.
Yep, saw it coming.
All right! I struck out!
Yay, struck out!
Yes! Safe!
But that doesn't make it suck any less.
I didn't get it.
Is something the matter, Amami-san?
Yes. I'd like to give the class
a piece of my mind.
Do you all hate Maehara-kun or something?
Translation: Sriram Gurunathan
Subtitle Editing: Geoff Mazzolini
Subtitle Timing: Krzysztof Kunc
Quality Check: Ashley Barboza
Translation Check: David Saylor
"The Two and Their School Festival."